Station from Patrol 48, grey
Aston Martin followed by
a bloack Alfa Romeo driving
towards the quarries.
Gunshot fire.
It's time to get out.
♪ Another ringer with the
slick trigger finger ♪
♪ For Her Majesty ♪
♪ Another one with
the golden tongue ♪
♪ Poisoning your fantasy ♪
♪ Another bill from a killer ♪
♪ Turned a thriller to a tragedy ♪
♪ A door left open ♪
♪ A woman walking by ♪
♪ A drop in the water ♪
♪ A look in the eye ♪
♪ A phone on the table ♪
♪ A man on your side ♪
♪ Oh, someone that you
think that you can trust ♪
♪ Is just another way to die ♪
♪ Another tricky little gun ♪
♪ Giving solace to the one ♪
♪ That will never
see the sunshine ♪
♪ Another inch of your life
sacrificed for your brother ♪
♪ In the nick of time ♪
♪ Another dirty money
heaven-sent honey ♪
♪ Turning on a dime ♪
♪ Well, a door left open ♪
♪ A woman walking by ♪
♪ A drop in the water ♪
♪ A look in the eye ♪
♪ A phone on the table ♪
♪ A man on your side ♪
♪ Oh, someone that you
think that you can trust ♪
♪ Is just another way to die ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ You know you're gonna die ♪
♪ Shoot 'em up, bang, bang ♪
♪ A door left open ♪
♪ A woman walking by ♪
♪ A drop in the water ♪
♪ A look in the eye ♪
♪ A phone on the table ♪
♪ A man on your side ♪
♪ Oh, someone that you
think that you can trust ♪
♪ Is just another way to die ♪
♪ Another ♪
♪ It's just another way ♪
♪ Shoot 'em up, bang, bang ♪
♪ You know you're gonna ♪
♪ Die ♪
♪ Just another ♪
♪ It's just another way ♪
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang ♪
Don't bleed to death.
- Hello, Mitchell.
- Bond.
The Americans are gonna be
none too pleased about this.
I promised them Le Chiffre,
and they got Le Chiffre.
They got his body.
If they'd wanted his soul, they should
have made a deal with a priest.
- Has he said anything?
- No.
I'm going to check the perimeter, ma'am.
You look like hell.
When's the last time you slept?
Vesper's boyfriend, Yusef Kabira,
the one who was abducted in Morocco,
the one she was trying to save.
His body was washed up
on a beach in Ibiza.
We're meant to believe the
fish did that to his face.
His wallet and ID were in his pocket.
- Well, that's convenient.
- Quite.
Which is why I did a DNA check on a lock
of his hair found in Vesper's apartment.
It's not him.
A lock of his hair?
I wouldn't have thought
Vesper the sentimental type.
Well, we never really know anyone, do we?
But I do need to know, Bond.
I need to know that I can trust you.
And you don't?
Well, it'd be a pretty cold bastard
who didn't want revenge for the
death of someone he loved.
You don't have to worry about me.
I'm not gonna go chasing
him. He's not important.
And neither was she.
It's clear, ma'am.
- Thanks, Mitchell.
- Shall we?
Are you gonna tell us who you work for?
I was always very interested to meet you.
I'd heard so much about you from Vesper.
The real shame is that if
she hadn't killed herself,
we would have had you, too.
I think you would have
done anything for her.
Well, you know you're not in Britain,
and God knows where you'll be tomorrow.
Which should tell you that eventually
you will tell us about the
people you work with,
and the longer it takes, the
more painful we'll make it.
You really don't know anything about us.
It's so amusing because we are
on the other side, thinking,
"The MI6, the CIA, they're
looking over our shoulders.
"They're listening to
our conversations."
And the truth is you don't
even know we exist.
Well, we do now, Mr White,
and we're quick learners.
Oh, really?
Well, then, the first thing
you should know about us
is that we have people everywhere.
Am I right?
Anything?
Craig Mitchell worked
for me for eight years.
He passed a full security check
and lie detector test every year.
Didn't leave so much as a scrap
of paper to explain any of it.
Eight years. Five as
my personal bodyguard.
I found this and three other
bloody Christmas presents
I bought him about the house.
I don't think he smoked.
And you had to kill him.
Couldn't bring him in for questioning so
that we might actually learn something.
When someone says we
got people everywhere,
you expect it to be hyperbole.
Lots of people say that.
Florists use that expression.
Doesn't mean that they've got somebody
working for them inside the bloody room.
What the hell is this organisation, Bond?
How can they be everywhere and
we know nothing about them?
I assume we found no trace of White.
No.
The agent guarding the door in the garage
was dead before you
passed him on the stairs.
I passed him on the
stairs? Christ.
Mitchell must have killed him when
he went out to check the perimeter.
You're lucky to be here.
Do you think White's still alive?
- Yes, I do.
- What is it?
Craig Mitchell, 45 years old.
No living family. Gave
generously to charity.
Tell me you know more than that.
Our moneymen went through every bill
in Mitchell's wallet and house.
- How much did he have?
- Less than 100 pounds,
and about the same in euros and dollars.
Excuse me. Excuse me, ma'am.
We've done a complete forensic analysis
of every note and its traceable history.
Not in the mood.
After you.
This particular note from Mitchell's
wallet may be of interest.
Scanning.
We introduced tagged bills into Le
Chiffre's money-laundering operation
by intercepting illegal pay-offs.
We traced money through several of
his bank accounts around the world.
That's pretty thin.
At the rate money changes hands,
you could probably find a
tenner in my wallet with a tag.
That's true, ma'am. A single
bill could be a coincidence,
but what about a whole stack?
These bills, from the same
series as Mitchell's,
were just scanned at a bank
in Port-au-Prince, Haiti,
deposited in the account of a Mr Slate.
Impress me.
We have a Mr Edmund Slate
returning to Port-au-Prince
from Heathrow this morning.
His entry documents have him
staying at the Hotel Dessalines.
He's in room 325.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Do you have any messages for 325?
No, sir. The only message
was about the briefcase
that was delivered earlier.
Did you want us to continue holding it?
No. No, I'll take that now.
Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Get in.
- What?
- Get in.
All right.
You're late.
I got pulled into a meeting.
Who with?
A friend of Mr White's.
Don't think I know him.
It's funny.
You don't look at all like I expected.
Really? What were you expecting?
I didn't think geologists looked so...
So?
A friend of yours?
I don't have any friends.
Get out of the way. Move.
We didn't settle on a price.
Make me an offer.
We can work it out later, over drinks.
Dominic didn't give you
any trouble, did he?
No.
What the hell is this?
I think someone wants to kill you.
That wasn't very nice.
- You were supposed to shoot her.
- Well, I missed.
Get Bond.
Where is he now?
Approaching the docks, Kings Quay.
- Connecting.
- Tanner.
I've got Bond.
Ask him about Slate.
She wants to know about Slate.
Tell her Slate was a dead end.
Slate was a dead end.
Connection terminated.
Damn him. He killed him.
Let her through.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Touch me and I'll break your wrist.
- We have a visitor.
- Not now, I'm busy.
Camille.
How nice to see you.
Alive, you mean?
I knew we shouldn't have slept together.
I think I'm starting to like you.
So you did just try and have me killed.
And that made me very sad thinking
I would never see you again.
But here you are.
Damn it, Dominic. I was
trying to help you.
I was trying to uncover a leak.
And you, you sent someone to kill me?
Please don't talk to me like I'm stupid.
It's unattractive.
Come. I wanna show you something.
Come.
There's nothing that makes
me more uncomfortable
than friends talking behind my back.
It feels like
ants under my skin.
It's been that way forever.
I remember when I was 15,
I had a crush on one of my
mother's piano students.
Somehow I overheard her saying
very nasty things about me.
I got so angry.
I took an iron.
Is that him?
I... We only spoke on the phone.
It's such a shame because he's
one of my best geologists.
He said you asked to buy information.
No. He called me and offered
to sell me information.
Why would I come back here if I was lying?
Because you love me.
I was doing it for you.
To stop him from betraying you.
You know what burns more
than all your bullshit?
Is that I always got the feeling
that you were only sleeping with me
to get to General Medrano.
Is that him?
You know how these deposed dictators are,
jealous of their safety.
Stick around.
I'll introduce you.
Do you see the girl that
just walked in here?
Could you give her that?
Tell her to call me.
What did he want?
He wants her to call him.
You've reached Universal Exports.
Our offices are currently closed.
Pay attention next time.
And you can do all this for me?
Well, look at what we did to this country.
The Haitians elect a priest
who decides to raise the minimum
wage from 38 cents to $1 a day.
Whoa.
It's not a lot, but it's enough
to upset the corporations
who were here making
T-shirts and running shoes.
So they called us, and
we facilitated a change.
The difference is,
my country's not some flyspeck
in the middle of the Caribbean.
But we've already begun
destabilising the government.
We'll supply the private security.
We'll pay off the right officials,
and we have 26 countries ready
to officially recognise
your new Bolivian government.
You want your country back.
My organisation can give
it to you within the week.
You've been busy.
And in return you want what?
A desert.
- This part.
- This land is worthless.
So you're getting a great deal.
You won't find oil there.
Everyone has tried.
Maybe, maybe not.
But we own whatever we find.
Did you know Ernesto Monies'?
A very powerful man in his day.
He had a beautiful Russian wife.
A dancer.
Well, his daughter works for me.
Or did.
She's lovely,
but I don't see the resemblance.
Why don't you consider her as
something to sweeten the deal?
Just promise me to drop her
over the side when you're done.
Camille, General Medrano.
I knew your family.
Sadly, I believe I was the
last to see them alive.
Be careful what you wish for, my dear.
Have fun, you two.
What the hell are you doing?
- You're welcome.
- You idiot. Take me back.
You know, maybe I'll do that later.
You're not one of Greene's.
Dominic Greene?
Get down.
- Give me the wheel.
- Navigate.
Left.
- What are you doing?
- Hold on.
Get down.
Excuse me.
Thank you. She's seasick.
It's Bond.
- Connect Bond.
- Connecting 007.
Yes?
Name check, Dominic Greene.
G-R-E-E-N-E.
I might need a little more than that.
There are a lot of Dominic Greenes.
Do you have a social
security or passport number?
No.
Scanning DGSE databases.
- Anything?
- Scanning KGB databases.
Do you have anything? Will
you put her on, please?
I am on, Bond. What
happened to Slate?
I'm not dwelling on the past.
I don't think you should, either.
You killed him.
Largest hit, Dominic Greene,
CEO of Greene Planet.
It's a utility company,
but Greene's been doing a
lot of philanthropic work,
buying up large tracts of land
for ecological preserves.
You should be getting his picture now.
Yep, that's him.
I'm afraid there's a firewall around
his other corporate holdings,
so we have no other information.
Get me the Americans.
Connecting.
Go ahead.
Interest in Dominic Greene, Greene Planet.
Transferring you now.
Hold for Gregory Beam, please.
Thank you.
Hi, this is Gregory Beam, ma'am.
Hello, Mr Beam.
I'm so sorry to keep you waiting.
We have no interest in Mr Greene.
Thank you, Mr Beam.
Connection terminated.
He's a person of extreme interest.
But he just said that he wasn't...
Tanner, I asked about the man
and she transferred me to the
section chief of South America.
How would she know to do that
if they weren't tracking him?
Bond, we have your location
as approaching an airfield.
- Is Greene on the move?
- Yeah.
I've got a tail number,
Golf-Zero-Charlie-Sierra-Charlie.
Get me a destination.
It's a private charter
going to Bregenz, Austria,
leaving immediately.
Tanner, authorise a charter for 007.
And, Bond, if you could avoid
killing every possible lead,
it would be deeply appreciated.
Yes, ma'am. I'll do my best.
Connection terminated.
I've heard that before.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Welcome aboard.
Come. Have a seat.
Charlie-Sierra-Charlie.
Jeez.
Sorry.
How much longer?
So do we have an understanding?
Yeah.
We do nothing to stop a coup
in Bolivia, and in exchange,
the new government gives America
the lease to any oil found.
If it's oil you want.
Well, you didn't find diamonds, did you?
Drilling underground, you kept off
everybody's radar for a very long time,
but you can't buy that much piping
without somebody getting curious.
We'll have to verify the find.
I'm not even admitting there is
one. You are getting
this for free.
Venezuela, Brazil, now Bolivia.
With you tied up in the Middle East,
South America is falling like dominoes.
You don't need another Marxist giving
national resources to the people, do you?
Well, we can hardly be expected
to do something about a coup
we know nothing about.
And I have a pest.
This.
You have any idea who that is?
Sorry.
It's James Bond, British Secret Service.
I don't know how I could have missed that.
I will need you to get rid of him for me.
Yeah. That's not
gonna be a problem.
You know who Greene is and you
wanna put us in bed with him.
You are kidding, right?
Yeah. You're right. We should
just deal with nice people.
I need to know you're on the team, Felix.
I need to know you value your career.
Dominic Greene.
- Good to see you. Good.
- How are you?
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight's performance of
Tosca will begin shortly.
Please take your seats.
What else does General Medrano require?
Anything further from
Canadian intelligence?
We'll discuss that later.
How much more pipeline do we need?
Ideally, 2,000 kilometres.
Are there any objections?
No.
Not here.
No objections.
Transfer the funds from
our Siberian holdings.
Done.
Where do the Americans stand?
Well, the CIA doesn't care about another
dictator as long as they get their end.
But when they find out
that they've been duped?
I'm working on that.
I'm still not sure that the Tierra Project
is the best use of Quantum's time.
Perhaps we should shift our
focus to the Canadian.
This is the world's
most precious resource.
We need to control as
much of it as we can.
Bolivia must be top priority.
Can I offer an opinion?
I really think you people should
find a better place to meet.
Where do you think you're going?
Thank you.
Well, Tosca isn't for everyone.
Drop it.
So who are you working for?
Piss off.
Get rid of anything we brought
with us. We've been compromised.
I asked you who you were working for.
- Is he one of ours?
- No.
Then he shouldn't be looking at me.
Get me M.
It's your line.
Thanks. Connect call.
Connecting Tanner.
We've ID 'd the pictures.
Show me.
Gregor Karakov, former minister, now
owns most of the mines in Siberia,
Moishe Soref, former
Mossad, now telecom giant,
and Guy Haines, special envoy
to the Prime Minister.
Get Bond.
There's something else.
It appears Bond shot Haines'
bodyguard and threw him off a roof.
- Where are you?
- Did you get my pictures?
Was this a conversation?
Can you link these people?
Is that stress in your voice?
I need you to come in and debrief.
I don't have time.
Bond, you killed a man in Bregenz.
I did my best not to.
You shot him at point blank
and threw him off a roof.
I'd hardly call that showing restraint,
especially since he was a
member of Special Branch.
So who was he guarding?
Bond, are you missing the fact
that you killed a member
of Special Branch?
I need you to come in.
And I would, but right now I need to
find the man who tried to kill you.
Go back to sleep.
Connection terminated.
Restrict Bond's movements.
Cancel his cards.
Put an alert on his
passports. All of them.
And I want to know everything
we don't know about Haines.
Yes, ma'am.
And, Tanner, be careful
who you trust with this.
Hopefully, you're a better
judge of character than I am.
You want to follow your
friends to La Paz, Bolivia?
Please.
I'm sorry, sir, but this doesn't work.
Do you have another card?
No.
Could you do me a favour?
You're gonna get a phone call in a minute.
Would you mind telling
them I'm headed for Cairo?
- I'd be happy to.
- Thank you.
(GREETING IN GERMAN)
Mathis.
What do you want?
Come to apologise?
You know, Mathis,
I think retirement suits you.
None for him.
Sorry. He's in a bad mood today.
This man had me imprisoned and tortured
and you want to serve him fine wine?
You only buy cheap wine.
And since you were innocent, they
bought you this villa.
So really you owe him, don't you?
Gemma, go work on your tan.
I need a passport and
matching credit cards.
And MI6 ran out of plastic?
Well, oddly, right now, you're the
only person I think I can trust.
That is odd.
But I guess when one's young,
it seems very easy to distinguish
between right and wrong.
But as one gets older, it
becomes more difficult.
The villains and the
heroes get all mixed up.
I was sorry to hear about Vesper.
I think she loved you.
Right up until the moment she betrayed me.
She died for you.
Why did you really want to see me?
I need some information.
You have some hard friends. This
man is some kind of facilitator.
Fingers in many pies, and
they don't leave any prints.
- These men were together?
- They're buying up oil pipeline.
Something called the Tierra Project.
- Do you know it?
- Destroy these.
That's Guy Haines.
You don't know him?
- Should I?
- I suppose not.
You haven't been keeping
secrets as long as I have.
He keeps a very low profile,
but he's one of the Prime
Minister's closest advisors.
Well, they say you're judged by
the strength of your enemies.
Do you know anything about Bolivia?
I was stationed in South
America for seven years.
Well, do you have some contacts there?
A few.
What do you want to know?
Come with me.
I want your hands on my skin.
You can't sleep?
May I fix you a drink, sir?
What are you drinking?
I don't know. What am I drinking?
Three measures of Gordon's
gin, one of vodka, half of...
Kina Lillet.
Kina Lillet, which is not Vermouth,
shaken well until it is ice-cold,
then served with a large
thin slice of lemon peel.
Six of them.
That's impressive.
They're good. You should have one.
No, it'll just keep me awake.
So what's keeping you awake?
I was wondering why you came with me.
It takes something to
admit you were wrong.
- You want a sleeping pill?
- No.
- Pain pill?
I have pills for everything.
Some make you taller.
Some make you forget.
I'm going to try and get some sleep.
Good idea.
Thank you.
Mr Bond, my name is Fields.
I'm from the consulate.
Well, of course you are.
And what do you do at
the consulate, Fields?
That's not important.
My orders are to turn you around
and put you on the first
plane back to London.
Do those orders include my friend Mathis?
I'm sorry, I don't know who you are.
You see that? Gone such a short
time and already forgotten.
You're just saying that to hurt me.
Mr Bond, these orders come from
the highest possible authority.
Taxi. Fields, when is the
next flight to London?
Tomorrow morning.
Well then, we have all night.
If you attempt to flee, I will arrest you,
drop you off in jail and take
you to the plane in chains.
- Understand?
- Perfectly. After you.
- I think she has handcuffs.
- I do hope so.
He blames the water
shortage on global warming.
Hello, Carlos? Carlos.
The Colonel who heads the National Police.
We have a reservation.
- Cémo esté?
- Very well, thank you.
- Your name?
- Miss Fields.
- You're going nowhere.
- So shoot me.
I'd rather stay in a morgue.
We are teachers on sabbatical.
This fits our cover.
No, it doesn't. Get in. Get in.
Follow me, please.
May I show you your room, senior?
No, it's fine. Thank you.
I can't find the...
The stationery.
Will you come and help me look?
You've been invited to a party.
I didn't know we had any friends here.
Greene Planet.
You're not coming?
I'm having a drink with
my friend the Colonel.
I'll see you there later.
Do you know how angry I am at myself?
I can't imagine.
You must be furious.
Do you want to go to a party?
A party?
But I have nothing to wear.
We'll fix that.
It might be useful to know your real name.
Fields.
Just Fields.
Fields it is, then.
We are in a spiral of
environmental decline.
Since 1945, 17% of the
planet's vegetated surface
has been irreversibly degraded.
The Tierra Project is just one small
part of a global network of ECO Parks
that Greene Planet has created
to rejuvenate a world on
the verge of collapse.
I hope that tonight you make the
decision to be part of that.
Thank you.
And have fun.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Excellent speech and congratulations.
Wonderful speech, Dominic.
- We need you here.
- Thank you.
Miss Fields, Mr Bond, my friend Carlos.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Ma'am.
Mr Bond, Mathis has spoken
a great deal about you.
I want you to know my entire
police force is at your disposal.
Well, that could be very useful.
You know, there are people in this
country spending half their pay cheque
just to get clean water.
What do you think of that?
The Bolivian government is the problem.
They cut down the trees,
then act surprised when the water
and the soil wash out to sea.
I couldn't agree more. I hope
this figure is to your liking.
Chéri, you shouldn't tease.
Why don't you tell them about all the
land you bought up outside Potosi'?
It's been a pleasure.
Will you excuse me?
Of course.
Somehow the logging rights
went to a multinational corporation
that out down the forests,
but only after our last government
sold the land to Greene Planet.
- Or have I got my facts crossed?
- Yes, I think you did.
You'll excuse us?
What a wonderful night.
You just cost me quite a
bit of money, darling.
You can't put a price on integrity.
I can try.
Oh.
Thank you.
Tell me you didn't drop by tonight
just to piss on my parade.
Or are you still after this
General's head for your mantel?
A little of both.
Tell me where Medrano is
and maybe you won't lose
any more investors.
You are really breaking my heart,
choosing an insect like that over me.
Are you going to throw me over?
No. You've been drinking,
so maybe you slipped.
Oh. Just think how
much you'd miss me.
Good evening.
There you are.
Would you excuse me?
Mr Bond.
What a pleasure.
Well, careful with this one.
She won't go to bed with you
unless you give her
something she really wants.
It's a shame because she's
really quite stunning
once you get her on her back.
I wish I could say the feeling was mutual.
I'm sorry, Mr Greene, but we have to go.
Please. My friends
call me Dominic.
I'm sure they do.
How much do you know about Bond, Camille?
Because he's rather a tragic case.
As MI6 says, he's difficult to control.
Nice way of saying that everything
he touches seems to wither and die.
Shall we?
Doesn't bode well for you, I'm afraid.
You two do make a charming couple, though.
You're both... What's
the expression?
Damaged goods.
Oh, my gosh.
I'm so sorry.
Come on, lighten up.
You're cramping my style.
So it's British intelligence now.
What the hell do you want from me?
You're gonna show me Dominic
Greene's Tierra Project.
- Are you up to it?
- Do I have a choice?
Do you want one?
There's something horribly
efficient about you.
Is that a compliment?
Well, what's the bet that Dominic
Greene has friends in the police force?
Stay here.
Papers, please.
Open the trunk.
Now, why would you want me to do that?
Get him out.
Hurry up.
He's moving.
Shoot him.
Mathis?
There's a hospital on
the other side of town.
Please.
Stay with me.
Stay here, please.
Please.
Come here.
It's okay.
That's better.
That doesn't hurt.
Is Mathis your cover name?
Yes.
Not a very good one, is it?
Do we forgive each other?
I shouldn't have left you alone.
Vesper.
She gave everything for you.
Forgive her.
Forgive yourself.
Is that how you treat your friends?
He wouldn't care.
Let's go.
The Foreign Secretary's asking to see you.
What don't I know?
Rene Mathis has been shot dead in Bolivia.
The police claim it was Bond.
How much did you pay him?
Well, he wanted you, but I left
him the car as collateral.
He'll make much more when he sells us out.
Right.
Let's see if this thing'll fly.
Here.
All the information I found said
there was nothing of value there,
but Greene's geologist had
proof that there was.
My sources tell me you're
Bolivian Secret Service,
or used to be,
and that you infiltrated Greene's
organisation by having sex with him.
- That offends you?
- No, not in the slightest.
So what's your interest in Greene?
Amongst other things, he tried
to kill a friend of mine.
- A woman?
- Yes.
But it's not what you think.
- Your mother?
- She likes to think so.
What's that down there?
That's a sinkhole.
There are a few around here.
Just for the record, I
wasn't with Greene for my...
Damn it.
I think we lost him.
He's coming fast.
He's right behind you.
Here. Put that on.
Come on.
Camille.
According to the Bolivians,
it was a routine stop,
and when they discovered Mathis'
body, Bond disarmed and shot them.
Of course, there are no
witnesses to prove otherwise.
I need something. I can't
go in there unarmed.
I'm sorry. There's nothing.
Come in.
What's today's excuse? That
Bond is legally blind?
No, Minister.
I don't think I need to tell
you how upset the P.M. is.
With respect, the P.M.
has my direct line.
And he'd have used it if
he'd wanted to speak to you.
I'm sorry, M. Things have changed.
We've had long discussions
with our cousins.
Mr Greene's interests and ours now align.
Minister, this man is
a major player in one
of the most dangerous organisations...
We've never even heard of.
Foreign policy cannot be conducted on
the basis of hunches and innuendo.
Then give us time to
gather enough evidence
so you can make informed decisions.
Fine.
Say you're right. Say
Greene is a villain.
If we refused to do
business with villains,
we'd have almost no one to trade with.
The world's running out of oil, M.
The Russians aren't playing ball.
The Americans and Chinese are
dividing up what's left.
Right or wrong doesn't come into it.
We're acting out of necessity.
Bond is running wild.
Who's to say he hasn't been turned?
Pull him in or the Americans
will put him down.
I think I found a way out.
You're freezing.
I'm fine.
So what is it that Greene
has that you want?
It's not Greene. It's Medrano,
the man he met in Haiti.
My father worked for the military junta.
He was a very cruel man,
but he was my father.
When I was a small child
the opposition sent General
Medrano to our house.
He shot my father.
He did things to my mother and my sister
and then strangled them while I watched.
I was too young to be any trouble,
so he just smiled at me
and set the house on fire.
He left his mark.
So when I pulled you off the boat...
I waited years for that chance.
I apologise.
It seems we're both using
Greene to get to somebody.
You lost somebody?
I did, yes.
You catch whoever did it?
No. Not yet.
Tell me when you do.
I'd like to know how it feels.
We should go.
You ready?
They used dynamite.
This used to be a riverbed.
Greene isn't after the
oil. He wants the water.
We can't leave it like this.
It's one dam. He's creating a
drought. He'll have built others.
Excuse me, sir. Your
wife left a message.
The English woman, she left
it for you this morning.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
What is it?
Would you mind waiting down here?
I'll be outside.
So that's what she meant.
I hope you can trust these men.
Just a moment. It's Tanner.
Yes?
We've got the girl downstairs.
She says to tell you she's sorry
but this is not her fight.
It isn't. Let her go.
She isn't our concern.
Well, I'm disappointed.
You are?
How much oil did the
Americans promise you?
This isn't about oil.
Well, that's good,
because there isn't any.
It's about trust.
You said you weren't motivated by revenge.
- I'm motivated by my duty.
- No.
I think you are so blinded
by inconsolable rage
that you don't care who you hurt.
When you can't tell your friends
from your enemies, it's time to go.
You might like to tell her your
theory about there being no oil.
Her lungs are full of it.
- It was Greene.
- No doubt. But why?
- It's just misdirection.
- I mean, why her, Bond?
She was just supposed
to send you home. She
worked in an office, collecting reports.
Look how well your charm works, James.
They'll do anything for you, won't they?
How many is that now?
You're removed from duty and suspended
pending further investigation.
You'll give whatever weapons you have
to these men and leave with them now.
Miss Fields showed true bravery.
I want that mentioned in your report.
Now you and I need to see this through.
There's nowhere to go.
There's a capture or
kill order out on you.
Who would have done that?
- Ma'am?
- Find out where he's going.
- He's on to something.
- Ma'am, the CIA is insisting...
I could give a shit about the CIA
or their trumped-up evidence.
He's my agent, and I
trust him. Go on.
- Get in.
- Are you gonna try and shoot me?
I said, get in.
You're gonna get botulism
if you keep drinking that.
It's bottled water.
It probably came from some stream
just around the corner from here.
Bunch of little kids peeing in it.
That's why I eat the peppers.
Well, all I'm saying is you can't
trust a damn thing around here.
You know, you should just
answer, "CIA," Felix.
A taxi driver told me
where the office was.
Well, if we're so easy to find,
James, you really should come visit.
Or maybe you should come out
and see some more of the city.
I heard a rumour you'd gone native.
Felix.
You know, I was just wondering
what South America would look like
if nobody gave a damn
about coke or communism.
It's always impressed me the way you
boys have carved this place up.
I'll take that as a compliment
coming from a Brit.
Are you sure you're playing
with the right side?
Regimes change once a week down here.
Medrano'll be no dirtier
than the next guy.
Oh, you see, that's what I
like about US intelligence.
You'll lie down with anybody.
Including you, brother.
Including you.
Do you know you're being played?
Dominic Greene's gonna
suck this place dry,
and then he's gonna move on,
and you're gonna be left
picking up the broken crockery.
What can I tell you? There's
no such thing as a free lunch.
Well, you see, Felix, I don't
think you're half as cynical
as you make out to be.
You don't know me.
Why? Just because you
didn't come alone?
- How long have I got?
- Thirty seconds.
Well, that doesn't give us
a lot of time, does it?
Medrano can't move until he pays
off the army and the police chief.
Greene's bringing him his money now.
A hotel called La Perla de Las Dunas
in the desert.
Thank you, Felix.
James, move your ass.
Get down. Get down, now.
Move it. Move it.
What the hell happened?
What did you tell him?
Just what we agreed.
What are you doing?
The slide's caught.
Maybe you should check your own.
I will.
Have you ever killed someone?
Your training will tell you that
when the adrenaline kicks in
you should compensate.
But part of you is not gonna believe the
training because this kill is personal.
Take a deep breath.
You only need one shot.
Make it count.
Asshole.
In euros,
as requested.
The dollar isn't what it once was.
The cost of war.
I am afraid that the corruption
in this current government
can no longer be tolerated.
And mine?
Right after you sign over my land.
My first official act.
And this, if you would.
What is this?
As of this moment,
my organisation owns more than
60% of Bolivia's water supply.
So this contract states
that your new government
will use us as utilities provider.
This is double what we are paying now.
Well, then don't sign it.
But you should know something about
me and the people I work with.
We deal with the left or the right,
with dictators or liberators.
If the current president
had been more agreeable,
I wouldn't be talking to you.
So, if you decide not to sign,
you will wake up with
your balls in your mouth
and your willing replacement
standing over you.
If you doubt that, then shoot me,
take that money and have
a good night's sleep.
You and I had a mutual friend.
Sounds like you just lost another one.
Not this way. Not this way.
I can't. I can't.
Come here.
Like you said,
"Take a deep breath.
"Make it count."
Close your eyes.
Come on.
Wait here.
- You promised that you'd...
- Let you go?
I answered your questions.
I told you what you wanted
to know about Quantum.
Yes, you did,
and your friends do know that so
they're probably looking for you.
But the good news is, you're
in the middle of a desert.
Here.
I bet you make it 20 miles before
you consider drinking that.
Goodbye, Mr Greene.
Thank you.
It's my pleasure.
Are you all right?
Fine.
But I keep thinking, "He's dead.
"Now what?"
Well, the dam we saw
will have to come down,
and there'll be others, too.
Someone who worked for
Greene might be of help.
Not a bad idea.
Do you think they'll be able to sleep now?
I don't think the dead
care about vengeance.
I wish I could set you free.
But your prison is in there.
Fine. Anything for an easy life.
Sit down.
It's okay, baby.
You're Canadian?
You work in Canadian intelligence?
It's all right. I know you do.
And knowing this man,
I'd guess you have access to
some very sensitive material
which you're gonna be forced to give up.
His life will be threatened,
and because you love
him, you won't hesitate.
It's a beautiful necklace.
Did he give it to you?
I have one just like it.
He gave it to a friend of mine,
someone very close to me.
Your name is?
- Corrine.
Corrine, I suggest you leave now.
You contact your people, and you
tell them to check their seals.
They have a leak.
Do it now, please.
This man and I have some
unfinished business.
Thank you.
Please.
Make it quick.
Is he still alive?
He is.
I'm surprised.
Did you find what you were looking for?
- Yes.
- Good.
- I assume you have no regrets.
- I don't.
What about you?
Of course not. That would
be unprofessional.
They found Greene dead
in the middle of the Bolivian
desert, of all places.
Two bullets in the back of his skull.
They found motor oil in his stomach.
Does that mean anything to you?
Wish I could help.
You'll be glad to know, I straightened
things out with the Americans.
Your friend Leiter's been promoted.
He replaced Beam.
Well, then the right
people kept their jobs.
Something like that.
Congratulations. You were right.
About what?
About Vesper.
Ma'am.
Bond,
I need you back.
I never left.